Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
Nicholas Roosevelt Papers
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Mabon, Mary Frost, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Macainag, Andres, 1932 (Box 8)
  - MacCormac, John, 1932 (Box 8)
  - MacDougal, Daniel T., 1954-1955 (Box 8)
  - MacMurray, John V. A., 1928 (Box 8)
  - MacNeil, Neil, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Mallory, Walter H., 1928 (Box 8)
  - Mantica, Margit Veszi, 1933 (Box 8)
  - Marriner, Guy, 1933 (Box 9)
  - Marshall, George C., 1926 (Box 9)
  - Martin, Lawrence, 1931 (Box 9)
  - Marvin, Langdon P., 1923; 1929,; 1953 (Box 9)
  - Mason, Julian S., 1926 (Box 9)
  - Matthews, Herbert Lionel, 1930 (Box 9)
  - Mayer, Ferdinand L., 1932 (Box 9)
  - Mayo, Katherine, 1930-1932 (Box 9)
  - McCutcheon, John Tinney, 1928-1930 (Box 9)
  - McPherson, Martha E., 1932 (Box 9)
  - Meloney, Marie Mattingly, 1929; 1931,; 1938 (Box 9)
  - Merrill, William K., 1962 (Box 9)
  - Meyer, C.F., 1926; 1930 (Box 9)
  - Millar, Melville B., 1974 (Box 9)
  - Miller, Henry, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Millet, J.B., 1930 (Box 9)
  - Moffat, John Pierrepont, 1932 (Box 9)
  - Moley, Raymond, 1940 (Box 9)
  - Monterey (CA) Board of Supervisors, 1966 (Box 9)
  - Monterey County (CA) Republican Central Committee, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Monterey Peninsula College, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Montgomery, John F., 1933-1946 (Box 9)
  - Moreno, Jose, 1931-1932 (Box 9)
  - Moro Commission on Separate Government, 1926 (Box 9)
  - Morrow, Dwight W., 1929 (Box 9)
  - Moseley, George Van Horn, 1930 (Box 9)
  - Moses, Robert, 1963-1967 (Box 9)
  - Mowrer, Paul Scott, 1930; 1943 (Box 9)
  - Munsterberg, Hugo, 1916 (Box 9)
  - M, miscellaneous, 1921-1960 (Box 9)
  - Nash, Ernest T., 1954 (Box 9)
  - National Park Service, 1926-1930; 1965 (Box 9)
  - Nature Conservancy, 1966-1968 (Box 9)
  - Navy League of the United States, 1930; list of ships (Oversize 17)
  - Neal, E. Virgil, 1931 (Box 9)
  - Netherlands Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1952 (Box 9)
  - Nevins, Allan, 1949-1960; 1965-1966 (Box 9)
  - New York World's Fair, 1935-1936 (Box 10)
  - Newell, Moyca, 1959 (Box 10)
  - Newell, Wilbur K., 1953 (Box 10)
  - Norman, Emile, 1957; undated (Box 10)
  - Norton, Garrison, 1929; 1956 (Box 10)
  - Noyes, Alexander Dana, 1931 (Box 10)
  - Oakes, John B., 1967 (Box 10)
  - O'Brien, Robert Lincoln, 1953 (Box 10)
  - Ochs, Adolph S., 1925; 1931,; undated (Box 10)
  - Orvis, Louise, 1927 (Box 10)
  - Osborne, Lithgow, 1915-1916 (Box 10)
  - Oulahan, Richard V., 1926; 1928,; 1930 (Box 10)
  - Owings, Margaret Wentworth, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Owings, Nathaniel A., 1956 (Box 10)
  - N-O, miscellaneous, 1923-1965 (Box 10)
  - Page, Frank C., 1930 (Box 10)
  - Parsons, Geoffrey, 1929-1933 (Box 10)
  - Payne, F. H., 1930 (Box 10)
  - Pelenyi, John, 1928-1933 (Box 10)
  - Pell, John, 1930-1932 (Box 10)
  - Pennell, Joseph, 1908 (Box 10)
  - Pershing, John J., 1926; 1966 (Box 10)
  - Philippine Islands, 1905; studies in Moro history, law, and religion (Box 10)
  - Philippine Islands, 1930; appointment of Vice Governor, congratulations (Box 10)
  - Philippine Islands, 1926-1930; 1936; miscellaneous correspondence (Box 10)
  - Philippine Society of Southern California, 1930 (Box 10)
  - Phillips, William, 1933 (Box 10)
  - Platt, S. Phelps, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Plemp van Duiveland, Lambertus Joannes, 1932 (Box 10)
  - Poor, Henry V. and Elizabeth, 1963; 1966,; 1972 (Box 10)
  - Porters, Robert, 1931-1932 (Box 10)
  - Pratt, William V., 1930 (Box 10)
  - Prince, John Dyneley, 1932-1933 (Box 10)
  - Prittwitz und Gaffron, Friederich von, 1930 (Box 10)
  - Procter, William, 1930; 1938 (Box 10)
  - Public Affairs Institute, 1949 (Box 10)
  - Putnam, Carlton, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - P, miscellaneous, 1927-1972 (Box 10)
  - Quezon, Manuel L., 1928-1930 (Box 10)
  - Radvanszky, Albert, 1931 (Box 11)
  - Reinhardt, Aurelia Henry, 1941 (Box 11)
  - The restless pacific, 1928; correspondence related to Roosevelt's book (Box 11)
    See also Writings: Books: The restless pacific.
  - Reston, James "Scotty", 1960; 1966 (Box 11)
  - Riis, Roger William, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Roberts, Roy, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Arthur R., 1929 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Corinne, 1931 (Box 11)
  - Robinson, Edgar and Lisette, 1948-1960; 1977 (Box 11)
  - Rockefeller, Nelson A., 1946 (Box 11)
  - Roerick, William, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt family, 1912; letters from Nicholas Roosevelt addressed to "Family" (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Archibald B., 1931; 1947-1960,; 1977-1978 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Andre and Anna, 1927; 1957 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Belle, undated (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Christine, 1930 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1936; 1938,; 1960,; undated (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1920; 1929-1943 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, George Emlen, 1944; 1953 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, James F., 1957 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, James West, 1872; 1886,; 1892,; 1894,; 1896,; 1927,; undated (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Jean, 1956; 1977 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Kermit, 1915 (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Laura Henriette, 1903; 1912-1916; 5 folders (Box 11)
  - Roosevelt, Laura Henriette, 1917-1945; undated; 8 folders (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Lorraine, See Warner, Lorraine Roosevelt.
  - Roosevelt, Oliver W., 1919; 1930-1933 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, P. James, 1966; 1979 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Philip, 1931; 1953 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Selwa, undated (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Silas Weir, 1846; 1851-1854; 1882,; 1908 (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Sr., 1899-1908; majority of correspondence between President Roosevelt and Nicholas's mother, Laura Roosevelt; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Sr., 1911-1916; undated; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Sr., 1902-1908; White House invitations; 5 folders (Box 13)
  - Roosevelt, Theodore Jr., 1932 (Box 13)
  - Roosevelt, Tweed, undated (Box 13)
  - Root, Elihu, 1933 (Box 13)
  - Royal Hungarian Legation, 1930 (Box 13)
  - R, miscellaneous, 1930-1957 (Box 13)
  - Sachs, Alexander, 1931 (Box 13)
  - Sackett, Frederick M., 1930-1933 (Box 13)
  - Saito, Hiroshi, 1932 (Box 13)
  - Salazar, R. Custodio, 1930 (Box 13)
  - Saltonstall, Leverett, 1927; 1929,; 1951,; 1959,; 1962,; 1978 (Box 13)
  - Sanborn, George, 1951-1952 (Box 13)
  - Sanger, Elliott M., 1956 (Box 13)
  - De Sarkany, Julius, 1931 (Box 4)
  - Satterlee, Herbert L., 1927-1930; 1938,; 1944,; 1947 (Box 13)
  - Sawada, Shinsaku, 1930 (Box 13)
  - Scenic Hudson Preservation Conference, 1962 (Box 13)
  - Schoenfeld, Rudolf E., 1931-1933; 1951,; 1977 (Box 13)
  - Schuyler, Louise Lee, 1916; 1924,; undated (Box 13)
  - J.H. Sears and Company, 1926-1927 (Box 13)
  - Sedgwick, Ellery, 1927 (Box 13)
  - Seldes, George, 1940 (Box 13)
  - Shaw, Albert, 1925 (Box 13)
  - Shaw, G. Howland, 1931-1933 (Box 13)
  - Shirer, William, 1932-1933 (Box 13)
  - Shotwell, James T., 1930-1932 (Box 13)
  - Siegfried, Andre, 1931; 1953-1956 (Box 14)
  - Sierra Club, 1947; 1965 (Box 14)
  - Simonds, Frank H., 1919 (Box 14)
  - Sizer, Theodore, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Smith, Corinna Putnam, 1930; 1950-1959 (Box 14)
  - The Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Speakers, University of Iowa, undated (Box 14)
  - The Society of American Historians, 1950 (Box 14)
  - Sonnenberg, Benjamin, 1938; 1953-1956 (Box 14)
  - Spice Islands Company, 1956-1957 (Box 14)
  - Standard Oil of New Jersey, 1940 (Box 14)
  - State Charities Aid Association, 1944-1945 (Box 14)
  - Steed, Wickham, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Stillman, Henry, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Stimson, Henry L., 1927-1930 (Box 14)
  - Stockton, Gilchrist B., 1932-1933 (Box 14)
  - Stokes, Harold Phelps, 1933; 1953,; 1956,; 1958 (Box 14)
  - Stone, David Lamme, 1939 (Box 14)
  - Stout, Rex, 1956 (Box 14)
  - Strawn, Silas H., 1927-1932 (Box 14)
  - Strong, Austin, 1931 (Box 14)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, 1930-1931; 1953,; 1958 (Box 14)
  - Sun Yat Sen Group, 1944-1945 (Box 14)
  - Swenson, Laurits S., 1932 (Box 14)
  - Szent-Györgyi, Albert, 1932 (Box 14)
  - S, miscellaneous, 1929-1966 (Box 14)
  - Taft, William Howard, 1926 (Box 14)
  - Taylor, Frank J., 1963; 1967 (Box 14)
  - Teleki, Pál, 1930; 1933,; 1941 (Box 14)
  - Temperley, Harold W.V., 1933 (Box 14)
  - Theodore Roosevelt Association, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Thompson, Carmi A., 1926 (Box 14)
  - Tilby, A. Wyatt, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Tobin, Richard M., 1925; 1930 (Box 14)
  - Toklas, Alice B., 1956 (Box 14)
  - Toolman, Harry, undated (Box 14)
  - Toynbee, Arnold J., 1950-1951; 1967 (Box 14)
  - Tredwell, Roger C., 1931 (Box 14)
  - Tsurumi, Yusuke, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Tuck, S. Pinckney, 1930 (Box 14)
  - Turner, Charles M., 1931 (Box 14)
  - Tyler, William Royall, 1931; 1966 (Box 14)
  - T, miscellaneous, 1930-1967 (Box 14)
  - United States Army, Reserve Officer Training Corps, 1917; 1919 (Box 14)
  - United States Bureau of Insular Affairs, 1926; 1930 (Box 14)
  - United States Department of Agriculture, 1957 (Box 14)
  - United States Department of Commerce Bureau of the Census, 1946 (Box 15)
  - United States Embassy, Budapest, Hungary, 1929 (Box 15)
  - United States Embassy, Paris, France, 1915; 1928; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - United States Embassy, Rome, Italy, 1931 (Box 15)
  - United States Legation, Budapest, 1932-1933 (Box 15)
  - United States Office of War Information, 1942-1943 (Box 15)
  - University of California, Los Angeles, 1962; 1966 (Box 15)
  - University of Oklahoma Press, 1953-1954; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Valentine, Alan and Lucia, 1955-1960 (Box 15)
  - Van Kleffens, Eelco, 1955; 1957 (Box 15)
  - Van Nuys, Frederick, 1939 (Box 15)
  - van Oss, Salomon Frederik, 1925-1933 (Box 15)
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H., 1938-1939 (Box 15)
  - Veloso, Antonio C., 1930 (Box 15)
  - Vertesy, Alexander de, 1933 (Box 15)
  - Villamin, Vicente, 1927; 1930 (Box 15)
  - Wadsworth, James W., 1937 (Box 15)
  - Wagner, Robert F., 1930; 1939 (Box 15)
  - Wainwright, J. Mayhew, 1930 (Box 15)
  - Warner, Langdon and Lorraine, 1915; 1933,; 1938,; 1959,; undated (Box 15)
  - Warner, Lorraine Roosevelt, 1914 (Box 15)
  - Warnshuis, Abbe Livingston, 1930 (Box 15)
  - Warren, Earl, 1943; 1949-1950 (Box 15)
  - Warren, Fletcher, 1954 (Box 15)
  - Watkins, Armitage, 1933; 1950-1960; 4 folders (Box 15)
  - Watkins, Armitage, 1965-1967 (Box 16)
  - Weingand, Alvin, 1965 (Box 16)
  - Welles, Sumner, 1953 (Box 16)
  - Wendell, Evert, 1923 (Box 16)
  - Weston, Edward, 1950-1952 (Box 16)
  - Wheeler, Raymond H., 1945 (Box 16)
  - White, John R., 1931 (Box 16)
  - White, Laura Chanler, 1915 (Box 16)
  - Whitney, Frederick C., 1956; 1959,; 1963 (Box 16)
  - Whittlesey, Charles B., 1944-1946 (Box 16)
  - Who's Who in America, 1947; 1950 (Box 16)
  - Whyte, William H., 1962, 1967; 1967 (Box 16)
  - Wile, Frederic William, 1930 (Box 16)
  - Wiley, Louis, 1929-1933 (Box 16)
  - Williams, Daniel R., 1926-1931 (Box 16)
  - Williamson, David, 1933 (Box 16)
  - Willkie, Philip H., 1953 (Box 16)
  - Willkie, Wendell L., 1940 (Box 16)
  - Willys, John N., 1932 (Box 16)
  - Wilson, Charles S., 1931 (Box 16)
  - Winslow, Rollin S., 1930-1933 (Box 16)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1917-1926; 1932 (Box 16)
  - WQXR, 1945-1950 (Box 16)
    See also Sanger, Elliot M.
  - Wright, J. Butler, 1930-1932 (Box 16)
  - Writer's Service Syndicate, 1930 (Box 16)
  - Wyeth, Marion Sims, 1931 (Box 16)
  - Wythe, George, 1932 (Box 16)
  - Yale University Press, 1933 (Box 16)
  - Ybarra, T.R., 1932 (Box 16)
  - Yosemite National Park, 1927 (Box 16)
  - Zsigmondy, Kalman, 1931 (Box 16)
  - Zwicky, Fritz, 1961 (Box 16)
  - W-Z, miscellaneous, 1928-1974 (Box 16)
  - Incomplete or illegible, 1914-1962; 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Incomplete or illegible, undated (Box 17)
- Financial and legal files
  - Contract agreements, 1926; 1952,; 1956,; 1959 (Box 17)
  - Contract for lease of the cutter Atlantico, 1932 (Box 17)
  - Expense accounts, 1925-1926; for Far Eastern trip (Box 17)
  - Invoices, receipts, royalty statements, etc., 1924-1930; 1954-1958 (Box 17)
- Memorabilia
  - Address book, Hungary and Austria, 1930-1933 (Box 17)
  - Awards and honors, decorations, Belgian and Hungarian, 1926 (Box 17)
  - Awards and honors, The Order of Merit of the Kingdom of Hungary, 1932 (Box 65)
  - Book reviews, clippings of reviews of Roosevelt's books
    - Creative cooking, 1957-1958 (Box 17)
    - A front row seat, 1953; 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Good cooking, 1959 (Box 17)
    - A new birth of freedom, 1938 (Box 17)
    - The Philippines: a treasure and a problem, 1926-1927 (Box 17)
    - The restless pacific, 1928 (Box 17)
  - Clippings
    - "Across the painted desert: Nicholas Roosevelt in Northern Arizona, 1913," The Journal of Arizona History, 1987 (Box 17)
    - The Continental Times, 1915; fragile newspaper clippings (Box 17)
    - The Continental Times, 1915; fragile newspaper clippings; 3 folders (Box 18)
    - Home and Garden, undated; 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Hungarian appointment, 1930; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Hungary, 1931-1932 (Box 19)
    - Philippines, 1927-1930; 4 folders (Box 18)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1883-1884; photocopies (Box 65)
    - Miscellaneous, 1916; 1918-1936; 1933-1949,; 1955-1959; 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Diaries, arranged chronologically; titles given below are as written on the item
    - [Untitled], 1906 (Box 66)
    - Travels in Arizona, 1911 (Box 19)
    - [Untitled], 1912 (Box 19)
    - Arizona, trip with Theodore Roosevelt, 1913; volumes 1-2; 2 folders (Box 19)
    - Paris diaries, 1914-1916; volumes 1-3; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Diary and letters from Spain, 1916-1917 (Box 20)
    - Austria and Hungary, 1918-1919; 4 folders (Box 20)
    - [Untitled], 1925 (Box 66)
    - [Untitled], 1929 (Box 20)
    - Budapest, 1930-1931 (Box 21)
    - Hungary, 1930-1933 (Box 21)
  - European trip, 1923-1924; includes money, addresses and itinerary, an introduction letter from Herbert Hoover (Box 21)
  - Evans School roster of former students, 1938 (Box 21)
  - Family papers (Box 21)
    - "Cousin Alice" recipe book, 1939 (Box 21)
    - D'Oremieulx-Gibbs records and letters
      This material was originally stored in a box which was written "D'Oremieulx-Gibbs records and letters." That heading, and the original order of material, have been retained. D'Oremieulx was the family name of Roosevelt's mother Laura.
      - [General], 1814-1891; 6 folders (Box 66)
      - [General], 1823; undated (Oversize 16)
      - Freemasonry Grand Orient de France, 1787 (Oversize 17)
      - French manuscript, circa 1720; bound volume by or about Pierre Jacques D'Oremieulx; includes printed biography by Laura D'Oremieulx is included and partly reads, "Pierre Jacques D'Oremieulx esquire, lord of Neuville, which estate he inherited from the de Laviers…he served as councilor of the king in the jurisdiction of Ponthieu and in the presidial court of Abbeville" (Oversize 6)
    - D'Oremieulx, Laura
      - Account book, 1879 (Box 22)
      - Diary, 1930-1931 (Box 22)
      - "Miscellaneous questions", 1871-1872; notebook with educational facts and notes (Box 22)
    - Genealogy, 1917-1939 (Box 21)
    - Genealogy, draft of booklet prepared by Laura D'Oremieulx, circa 1940 (Box 21)
    - Genealogy, prepared by Dixon Wector, undated; 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Genealogy, Roosevelt family, 1950; 2 folders (Box 22)
    - Roosevelt, Clinton, 1833; photocopy of his book, The mode of protecting domestic industry, consistently with the desires both of the south and the north, by operating on currency (Oversize 16)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1894; 1904,; 1910-1912; copies of letters (Box 66)
  - In memoriam of Abraham Lincoln, 1865; printed collection of Lincoln's speeches (Box 22)
  - Invitation to Nicholas Roosevelt from President Woodrow Wilson and the French Ambassador of the United States, 1918 (Box 22)
  - Maps
    - Europe, undated (Box 64)
    - Glason's auto-special map of Arizona, undated (Box 22)
  - Memoranda for Nicholas Roosevelt, 1924-1925 (Box 22)
  - Oral history interview with Nicholas Roosevelt by Raymond Henle, 1967; transcript of interview done for Herbert Hoover Presidential Library (Box 23)
  - Oral history interview with Nicholas Roosevelt by Raymond Henle, 1967; trancscript of interview done for Herbert Hoover Presidential Library (Box 69)
  - Passport, 1919; Roosevelt's special passport for conducting government business in Europe (Oversize 16)
  - Photographs
    - Roosevelt, Nicholas, undated (Box 23)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1902; undated (Box 23)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, undated (Oversize 16)
    - Through the painted desert, undated; negatives (Box 23)
  - Postcards
    - Schuyler mansion (Box 23)
    - Washington D.C. and President Theodore Roosevelt, 1901-1905 (Box 23)
  - Programs (Box 23)
  - Programs, "Peace jubilee and Roosevelt reception," Oyster Bay, L.I., Sep 21, 1898 (Box 23)
  - Promotional material, 1935; 1956; promotions for a lecture series delivered by Roosevelt, includes a biographical sketch of Roosevelt (Box 23)
  - Scrapbooks
    - America and England?, 1930; scrapbook of clippings and reviews relating to Roosevelt's book (Oversize 15)
    - Articles by Roosevelt, 1935-1937 (Box 23)
      See also Writings: Articles.
    - Clippings about Roosevelt, 1932-1933 (Oversize 9)
      See also Memorabilia: Clippings.
    - Clippings about Roosevelt, 1935-1936 (Oversize 13)
    - Clippings about Roosevelt, 1936-1937 (Oversize 10)
    - Clippings about and articles written by Roosevelt, 1922-1930 (Oversize 11)
    - Clippings about and articles written by Roosevelt, undated (Box 24)
    - China, Japan, and Philippines, 1926-1927 (Box 24)
    - Conservation: now or never, 1970; scrapbook of clippings and reviews relating to Roosevelt's book (Oversize 14)
      See also Correspondence-subject files: Conservation: Now or never.
    - Creative cooking, 1956 (Oversize 1)
    - Editorials by Roosevelt, 1934 (Box 24)
      See also Writings: Editorials.
    - Editorials by Roosevelt, 1936-1938; 3 volumes (Box 25)
    - Editorials by Roosevelt, 1940-1942; 2 volumes (Box 26)
    - Editorials and articles by Roosevelt, 1934 (Box 26)
    - Editorials and articles by Roosevelt, 1933-1935; 3 volumes (Box 27)
    - Editorials and articles by Roosevelt, 1935-1939; 3 volumes (Box 28)
    - Editorials and articles by Roosevelt, 1939-1940; 2 volumes (Box 29)
    - France trip, 1914-1915 (Box 29)
    - A front row seat, scrapbook of clippings and reviews relating to Roosevelt's book (Oversize 1)
    - Hungary (Oversize 5)
    - Hungary and the Philippines, 1930-1933; regarding Roosevelt's assignments (Oversize 4)
    - A new birth of freedom, 1938; scrapbook of clippings and reviews relating to Roosevelt's book (Oversize 8)
    - Newspaper articles, 1926-1930; 2 volumes (Oversize 2)
    - Newspaper articles, 1926-1930; 2 volumes (Oversize 3)
    - Theodore Roosevelt: The man as I knew him, scrapbook of clippings and reviews relating to Roosevelt's book (Oversize 7)
      See also Writings: Books: Theodore Roosevelt: The man as I knew him.
    - "Tribune" articles and editorials by Roosevelt, 1921-1923; scrapbook in poor and fragile condition (Oversize 12)
    - Trip around the world, 1915; 1925-1926 (Box 29)
  - Tourism magazines, Monterey Peninsula and Big Sur (Box 30)
  - Travel itinerary, undated (Box 30)
  - World War I propaganda and clippings, 1915 (Box 65)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - Asia magazine, 1934; regarding Japan (Box 30)
    - China, 1926; drafts (Box 30)
    - Conservation and Informed Public Opinion, 1946 (Box 30)
    - Foreign Affairs, 1929-1960; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - National Republican Builders, 1935-1936; 2 folders (Box 30)
    - Newspapers
      - The Annalist, 1924 (Box 30)
      - Austria and Hungary, 1919; 2 folders (Box 30)
      - Christian Science Monitor, 1934 (Box 30)
      - European trip, 1923-1924 (Box 30)
      - Far eastern trip, 1925-1926; a series of articles that Roosevelt wrote about Asia for The New York Times (Box 30)
      - Foreign, articles that Roosevelt wrote for foreign newspapers
        - Dutch, 1919; 1923 (Box 30)
        - Dutch, 1921-1924 (Box 66)
        - French, 1921-1923; 4 folders (Box 31)
        - German, 1922 (Box 31)
        - Le Temps, 1922-1925; 6 folders (Box 31)
        - Le Temps, 1922-1925; 3 folders (Box 32)
        - Le Temps, 1922 (Box 66)
        - Neue freie presse, 1919 (Box 32)
      - Foreign Affairs, 1912; 1922-1934 (Box 66)
      - Los Angeles Times, 1929 (Box 32)
      - New York Herald Tribune, 1923; 1933-1940; 6 folders (Box 32)
      - New York Times, 1923-1933; 1938; 2 folders (Box 32)
      - This Week, 1938-1939 (Box 32)
      - Washington Conference on Limitations of Naval Armaments, 1921 (Box 32)
      - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 33)
    - "The Roosevelt record", undated; galley proofs (Box 66)
    - Washington naval conference, circa 1922 (Box 33)
    - Unpublished, 1933-1939, 1966; 1966 (Box 33)
    - Untitled, undated (Box 33)
  - Books
    - Creative cooking
      - Drafts
        - Table of contents, acknowledgments, foreword, Chapters 1-6, undated; 12 folders (Box 33)
        - Chapters 6-18, undated; 17 folders (Box 34)
        - Postscript, index, fragments, undated; 3 folders (Box 35)
      - Galley proofs, 1956; 2 folders (Box 67)
      - Jacket copy, undated (Box 35)
      - Proof, 1957 (Box 35)
      - Research notes
        - Campbell Soup Company, 1953-1956 (Box 35)
        - Directions for cooking Borden's meat biscuit, 1955 (Box 35)
        - House of herbs, undated (Box 35)
        - Pressure Cooking Institute, undated (Box 35)
        - United States Department of Agriculture, 1951-1956 (Box 35)
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 35)
      - Specifications, undated (Box 35)
    - Divided They Stand, 1930; manuscript (Box 35)
    - Economic forces in the development of American history
      - Drafts
        - "Food", undated (Box 35)
        - "Health", undated (Box 36)
        - "Immigration", undated (Box 36)
        - "Isolation", undated (Box 36)
        - "Politics", undated (Box 36)
        - "Religion", undated (Box 36)
        - "Social", undated (Box 36)
        - Fragments, undated (Box 36)
      - Notes and research, undated; 6 folders (Box 67)
      - Notes and research, 1941-1951; 3 folders (Box 68)
      - Outline, undated (Box 36)
    - A front row seat
      - "As published," Chapters 1-30, 1966; 3 folders (Box 36)
      - Blurb, undated (Box 36)
      - Carbons and notes #1, undated (Box 36)
      - Carbons and notes #2, undated (Box 37)
      - Corrections, undated (Box 37)
      - Drafts
        - Blurb, table of contents, Chapters 5-32, epilogue, undated; 9 folders (Box 37)
        - Pages 1-210, undated; 2 folders (Box 37)
        - Pages 211-333, undated (Box 38)
      - Early drafts
        - Chapters 1-30, epilogue, 1950; 6 folders (Box 38)
        - "Birth of Bull Moose", undated (Box 39)
        - "The break-up of an empire", undated (Box 39)
        - "China", undated (Box 39)
        - "Diplomats, archdukes and aristocrats", undated (Box 39)
        - "The dust of New York", undated (Box 39)
        - "The east through Dutch eyes", undated (Box 39)
        - "From Manila to Budapest", undated (Box 39)
        - "A gallery of individualists", undated (Box 39)
        - "Goodbye to Europe", undated (Box 39)
        - "A Habsburg postlude", undated (Box 39)
        - "Hungary", undated; 3 folders (Box 39)
        - "Other presidential aspirants", undated (Box 39)
        - "Paradise on Long Island", undated (Box 39)
        - "Spanish interlude", undated (Box 39)
        - Fragments, undated; 4 folders (Box 40)
      - Extracts, 1953 (Box 40)
      - First draft
        - Table of contents, undated (Box 40)
        - Chapters 1, 3, 22, undated; 3 folders (Box 40)
        - Chapters "B-E", undated; 4 folders (Box 40)
      - Research notes (Box 40)
      - Rough draft
        - Pages 2-136, undated (Box 41)
        - "Americanizing Malays", undated (Box 41)
        - "Arizona", undated (Box 41)
        - "Herald Tribune", undated (Box 41)
        - "In the neighboring capitals", undated (Box 41)
        - "MacArthur", undated (Box 41)